# YOONJOO LEE

## yil7436@gmail.com | yoonjoolee.com

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest lies in the intersection of human-computer interaction (HCI) and natural language processing (NLP). I aim to support people to perform tasks ranging from teaching to writing effectively by 1) building AI-powered systems with humans in the loop and 2) expanding and adapting large-scale data and models to fit specific user tasks. Specifically, one of my research goals is to create computational methods and systems that support scalable teaching and learning using human-AI collaboration.

#### **EDUCATION**

KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science, Advisor: Juho Kim Sep. 2020 - Present

**Ewha Womans University** Seoul, Republic of Korea

M.S. in Statistics (Applicational Statistics), Advisor: Dongwan shin Mar. 2018 – Feb. 2020 Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018 B.S. Major in Mathematics Education, Minor in Statistics

Graduated with Honors (Magna Cum Laude)

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA, USA Exchange student in Mathematics Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## **Conference and Journal Papers**

# [C4] Promptiverse: Scalable Generation of Scaffolding Prompts Through Human-AI Hybrid Knowledge Graph Annotation

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Tae Soo Kim, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

CHI 2022: Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. To appear.

# [C3] Personalizing Ambience and Illusionary Presence: How People Use "Study with Me" Videos to Create **Effective Studying Environments**

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Jean Y. Song, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

CHI 2021: Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

# [C2] A Machine Learning Approach that meets Axiomatic Properties in Probabilistic Analysis of LTE Spectral **Efficiency**

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

ICTC, Oct. 2019

#### [C1] Probabilistic Analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE based on PDCCH Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Yeonkyu Park, Seungken Park

IEEE Communications Letters, vol. 23, no. 9, Sep. 2019

## **Posters and Workshop Papers**

## [P4] Interactive Children's Story Rewriting Through Parent-Children Interaction

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

Last Updated: May 9, 2022

ACL 2022 Workshop on Intelligent and Interactive Writing Assistant

## [P3] XDesign: Integrating Interface Design into Explainable AI Education

Hyungyu Shin, Nabila Sindi, **Yoonjoo Lee**, Jaeryoung Ka, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim *SIGCSE TS 2022 Posters* 

## [P2] A Study on the Distribution Analysis of LTE Resource Block Usage from TSME Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

# [P1] A Study on the Estimation of Probability Distribution of the Spectral Efficiency of LTE based on TSME Measurement Data

Yunbae Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

KIXLAB, KAIST

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Intern

 $Mar.\ 2020-Aug.\ 2020$ 

• Investigated user experiences with VR services by analyzing large-scale text data using various techniques like clustering, topic modeling, and sentiment analysis.

#### **Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)**

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Assistant, Data Sciences Group

Mar. 2018 – Dec. 2019

- Performed analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE with probabilistic modeling and Deep Neural Networks. [P1, C1, C2]
- Participated in research about predicting future Resource Block Usage by applying stochastic modeling and Recurrent Neural Networks. [P2]

Undergraduate Research Intern, Data Sciences Group

Jan. 2018 – Feb. 2018

• Devised a module for pre-processing and summarizing mobile traffic data in Python

# **PATENTS**

Domestic Patent: "Apparatus and Method for Stochastic Analysis of Spectral Efficiency and Transmission Rate of LTE"

#### **TEACHING**

# **Introduction to Social Computing**

Fall 2020, Fall 2021

KAIST CS473, Instructor: Juho Kim

Time Series Analysis Spring 2019

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Dongwan Shin

Regression Analysis Fall 2018

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Donghwan Lee

#### **SERVICES**

#### Reviewer

CHI 2022, C&C 2022, IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies

2021 – Present

Last Updated: May 9, 2022

Student Volunteer CHI 2022	2021
KAIST-Google ExploreCSR Student Organizer	2022 – Present
Programming Mentoring Leader of Student Organizer	2016 – 2017
Mathematics Mentoring in Ewha Girl's High School  Mentor	2015 – 2017
HONORS, AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS	
Research Assistant Scholarship College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University	2019
Admission Scholarship College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University	2018
Honors Scholarship College of Education, Ewha Womans University	2014, 2015, 2016, 2017
Dean's List College of Education, Ewha Womans University	2014, 2015, 2016, 2017
Ewha Womans University Alumnae Association Scholarship College of Education, Ewha Womans University	2017